+1-919-537-9807 225 Catalpa St, #205 San Mateo, CA

Summary

With engineering experience across the stack, I enjoy both technical and creative aspects of product development. I put people first, identify growth opportunities and bring them together to build a highly functional team who have then built amazing features.

Employment

Engineering Manager, Linden Labs
 Sansar – MMO VR Platform

May 2017 – Present

Technology: C++, Kafka, MVVM, Kanban

- Led strategic gameplay features from inception to launch, increasing Day 3 user retention 3X
- Bootstrapped commerce store which increased sales conversion and has a 90% traffic adoption rate
- Defined strategic direction of product working closely with product and project Manager
- Ran a team of 6 engineers spanning geographic locations and job functions
- Hands on with design discussions and code reviews with engineers
- Mentored engineers from different backgrounds and helped them grow in their careers
- Align engineers' aspirations with strategic opportunities for the company leading to a win-win
- Identified risk and blockers, and cleared the critical path for on-time delivery
- Enabled transparency across stakeholders and engineers using Jira's Kanban methodology
- Responsible for handling outages and coordinating efforts to get them resolved in a timely manner
- Evolved the UI infrastructure which decreased development time and established standard idioms

Lead Engineer, Cavium Inc. (acquired by Marvell Tech) SDK development

Feb 2014 - May 2017

Technology: C, C++, Python, GDB, Valgrind

- Drove the effort to open source SDK & worked on shaping the SDK from inception to launch
- Member of the gatekeeper team responsible for reviewing APIs for performance & memory leaks
- Coached and ramped up junior engineers on the team
- Fixed memory leaks in simulator from 1.9Mb to 0 bytes/packet using Valgrind
- Designed and implemented network topology to simulate single unit, multiple devices to communicate with outside world and each other using TAP interfaces, python and xml config

Software Engineer, nVidia Graphics Technology: C++, WinDbg

Oct 2012 - Feb 2014

- Implemented power management and a tool which deals with hysteresis for Windows Blue & Win8
- Implemented display context switching on the fly between native GPU and nvidia GPU
- Lead initiative to ensure both new and old features are backwards compatible with changing hardware

Software Engineer, WeAreHolidays Pvt Ltd. Travel Web platform

Jan 2012 - Sep 2012

Technology: Java, JPA, Maven, Struts 2, Spring 3, MySQL, Guava

- Developed the core API of the product, with performance and design as its key focus
- Integrating external APIs for rapid prototyping new ideas
- Lead team of 3 people to deliver product with zero codebase and aggressive timelines
- Defined agile processes to improve productivity and bring visibility in team performance

Software Engineer, hi5 Networks Social gaming/commerce platform Technology: C#, WCF, SQL Server 2010

May 2011 – Oct 2011

- Developed commerce portal with a pluggable architecture integrating multiple payment providers
- Developed end-to-end Credit Card payment system with PCI security compliance
- Developed Analytics API which enabled game developers to publish events consumed by BI team

Software Engineer(Contractor), Verizon Technology: C++, Python

Nov 2010 – Apr 2011

- Developing framework for inserting ads in HTTP live video streaming on server side
- Prototype adaptive bitrate video streaming media player on android OS

- Maintain legacy code and integrate it with newly developed product for backward compatibility
- Software Engineer(Contractor), Electronic Arts FIFA 3DS (Nintendo 3DS)

July 2010 - Oct 2010

Technology: C++, C#, ActionScript2, Nant Scripts, Python

- Implemented rendering primitives to support in-game User Interface elements in depth
- Collaborated extensively with the UI designer to get menu system working in game
- Managed the build process to support asset pipeline & multiple build configurations
- Worked closely with other team members to ensure project deliverables are completed on-schedule

Independent Projects

WordsAway

May 2016 – May 2017

Unity/Android Indie Game Technology: C#, Unity, Python

- Built this indie game from grounds up with the only engineer on the team and over 10K+ downloads
- Leveraged metrics to identify hotspots and improved player on-boarding from 20% to 80%
- Implemented Player Assist for balancing the game leading to better completion rates
- Architected Event Aggregator using publisher/subscriber and generics for decoupling modules
- Implemented Trie data structure optimized for space and constant lookup time
- Developed a level editor for game designers to adjust the game play & build new levels
- Enabled artists to associate FX prefabs with game events by implementing generic Unity components
- Designed object allocation/reuse by dynamically creating object pools with a tight upper bound
- Procedurally generated letters optimized to use only one sharing material / texture atlas
- Designed & implemented special powerups based on event aggregator module
- Implemented menu navigation (including popups) by dynamically loading different scenes
- Dynamically updating letters using shaders to reflect score multipliers / selected state

HoloHear (Hololens)

- Developed app for people with hearing disabilities to translate words to sign language in realtime
- The app won first prize amidst 20 teams at the Microsoft SF Hololens hackathon

Kolor (PC)

Technology: C++, OpenGL, Qt Framework, Boost, OpenGL Mathematics

- Designed 3D First Person Shooter with a unique game mechanic of claiming enemies by coloring
- Developed collada-DAE importer to use 3D models into the game
- Generated Collision detection Bounding Spheres hierarchy information for the imported DAE model
- Implemented efficient hash-based collision detection/resolution for players and bullets

High Dynamic Range Images Tack along Mattack

Technology: Matlab

- Implemented HDR algorithm to retrieve the original color response function for a natural scene
- Final image result closely resembles natural scene and lighting conditions as seen with naked eye

Education

University of North Carolina, Charlotte

MS in Computer Science (Graphics and Visualization)

May 2010 GPA: 3.8/4.00

U.P. Technical University (India)

BS in Computer Science (Software Development)

July 2006